Matthew Balaam



info@matthewbalaam.co.uk @matthewbalaam mattybalaam 07730 953 486 Flat 3, 11 Medina Villas Brighton and Hove BN3 2RJ Strong front-end developer able to adapt to full-stack within team projects. Agile learner with a curiousness toward innovative problem solving, and eagerness to update skills and knowledge to remain responsive to evolving technologies and market demands.

Main skill set in JavaScript, CSS, HTML with experience using reactive frameworks and cross-browser knowledge.

Previous background in graphic design and multimedia with an eye for accuracy and the little details to make projects stand-out.

This CV is built as a bespoke React app, review the code on Bitbucket

Technologies

- JavaScript
- · CSS and processors
- HTML
- React

- Redux
- CranhOl Analla
- GraphQL, Apollo
- TypeScript, ES2016, Babel
- Webpack
- PHPGit
- Node

Experience

2018 – 2018 JavaScript Engineer

Simpplr

simpplr.com

Building features on two React single page web apps in the corporate intranet sector. One an established product using React and Redux, and a more modern product using React with Apollo/GraphQL.

Working in an Agile environment using elements borrowed from Scrum and Kanban methodologies

2017 – 2018 Software developer

Filmstro

filmstro.com

Building cross-platform adaptive-music desktop app Filmstro Pro: A React/Redux app inside Electron communicating with a lower-level audio binary.

Building new features, improving performance and fixing bugs. Providing input on UI and UX from prototype to final feature. Migrated build from Gulp to Webpack, writing automated end-toend testing from specs by lead tester.

Working on corporate website built using Laravel with the Voyager CMS, primarily helping with cross-browser consistency.

Working using a Kanban Agile framework with daily stand-ups.

Meeting with the product owner and 4 other devs to prioritise stories, tasks and bugs, sub-tasks then decided among devs.

2013 – 2017 Front-end developer

New Era Education Ltd.

neweraed.co.uk

Sole developer on all company public-facing websites using JavaScript, CSS (SASS/PostCSS) and webpack, with SilverStripe (PHP) providing an MVC framework (HTML templating, SQL, and an easy-to-use CMS for content editors.

Working in a team on DB Primary, a safe, easy-to-use internet experience for pupils and teachers with a Java backend.

Creating interactive learning materials and assessed games. Developing an easy-to-use activity builder tool allowing teachers to set their own quizzes and surveys.

2009 – 2013

Freelance

Developer and designer

matthewbalaam.co.uk

Building bespoke responsive websites with concise, accessible, standards compliant, device responsive HTML and CSS, JavaScript and PHP to work over all major browsers.

stage

Designing and developing interactive E-learning courses at all stages from art-direction to final built course.

Creating a wide range of printed materials, emails and animated banners. Sourcing and liasing with print suppliers.

2001 – 2009

Graphic designer

Design conception through to final artworking on a very broad range of print and digital projects. Working in a collaborative design team. Liaising with all departments, as well as external clients and printers.

Newsquest Media

1997 – 2001 Artworker

Mostly print-based work using applications including Illustrator, Photoshop, Fireworks and QuarkXPress in a time-critical daily newspaper work environment.

Education

Southampton Solent University

Archant Media

Media and Cultural Studies The practical half of this degree covered web design, television and radio production, desktop publishing, journalism and photography. These creative practices were informed by studying strands of critical theory with an emphasis on how these can assist the creative process.

BA (Hons) 1993 – 1996